（未知来电）
（我妈出差 过来玩 免费晚餐）
（安珀：再加码）
（酒柜解锁）
（安珀：成交）
（未知来电）
（电话一直响个不停）
（安珀：卫斯还在烦你吗）
- 喂 - 你好
- Hello? - Hello.
克莉丝汀娜在吗
Is Cristina there?
她不在 你要留言吗
No, she's not available. May I take a message?
抱歉 我是她聚会的朋友 该死
Yeah, sorry. I'm a friend from her group… Oh, shit.
她的什么
From her shit?
跟她说我是聚会的查理 她有我号码
Look, just tell her I'm from group. I'm Charlie. She's got my number.
她参加你的聚会
Oh, she goes to your group?
我不应该…
I shouldn't have, um…
跟她说查理打来
Look, just tell her Charlie called.
没问题 查理
And I will do exactly that, Charlie,
但你得告诉我是什么会
once you tell me what kind of group we're talking about.
戒酒无名会戒毒会
Is it AA? NA?
你听起来跟她说的一样
You sound exactly like she describes you.
她在聚会上说到我
Uh, does she talk about me in group?
我不方便多说
Uh, I don't think I can really talk about that.
她是怎么说我的
What does she say about me?
她很爱你
Well, she loves you very much.
她爱我什么
What does she love about me?
她爱你充满创意
She loves that you're creative.
你喜欢艺术也爱看电视 电影
You love art and TV and movies.
很多人都爱看电影
Okay, well, lots of people love movies.
对 但她说你爱看恐怖片
Yeah, but she says you love scary movies.
那是你们的共同兴趣
and that you guys have that in common.
她把你调教成恐怖片迷很骄傲
She's proud of making a fan out of you.
- 是吗 - 是啊
- She is? - Yeah.
前几天她跟我说 她在猜…
Well, she told me the other day, she wonders…
你最喜欢哪部恐怖片
what's your favorite scary movie?
《鬼敲门》
Uh… The Babadook.
探讨身为人母的悲伤与哀愁
It's an amazing meditation on motherhood and grief.
不会有点假掰吗
Isn't that a little fancy pants?
那算是高级恐怖片
Well, it's elevated horror.
高级恐怖片是什么意思
Uh-huh. What does that mean, "Elevated horror"?
除了吓人还有复杂情感和深层主题
You know, it's scary but with complex emotional and thematic underpinnings.
不只是低级老套和不合理的突发惊吓
It's not just some schlocky, cheeseball nonsense with wall-to-wall jump scares.
听起来很无聊
Hmm. Sounds kind of boring to me.
你看过《惊声尖叫》吗
Have you ever seen Stab?
好像看过一次
Once, I think.
12岁去朋友家过夜看的
At a sleepover when I was, like, 12.
你住在伍兹柏勒不知道《惊声尖叫》
You live in Woodsboro and you don't know Stab?
你妈超爱那部电影 老是在聚会上说
Your mother loves that movie. She talks about it all the time in group.
原版电影你记得多少
How well do you remember the original?
不知道 超90年代的fu
I don't know. I mean, it was super '90s.
灯光打太亮 演员发型都很俗
It was really over-lit and everyone had weird hair.
记得开场戏吗
Uh-huh. Do you remember the beginning?
不记得
Not really.
一定是杀人场景 都嘛是这样
It started with a kill scene, right? They always started with a kill scene.
是啊 一点都没错
Yeah, that's right. That's right.
一名少女独自在家
It's a girl at home, alone.
接错电话然后开始跟凶手聊天
She answers a wrong number and starts talking with the killer.
他要她玩一个游戏
who makes her play a game.
你想玩一个游戏吗…
Would you like to play a game…
塔拉
Tara?
（门都已上锁）
保全系统启动
All systems armed.
（是个变态 我正在锁门）
（安珀：什么你没事吧）
（没事）
（安珀：你应该接电话）
（你怎么知道我的市话在响）
（安珀）
（我不是安珀）
（快接电话 小贱货）
（不接电话安珀就会死）
这不好笑 安珀
This isn't fucking funny, Amber.
我说过 我不是安珀
I told you, this isn't Amber.
安珀今晚看起来特别漂亮
Amber's looking particularly fetching tonight.
她不该随便乱放手机让别人复制
She really shouldn't leave her phone lying around for anyone to clone.
你想要什么
What do you want?
我说过 我想玩一个游戏
I told you, I want to play a game.
三个《惊声尖叫》问答题
Stab movie trivia, three rounds.
你报警她就死 答错了她就死
You call the cops, she dies. You get a question wrong, she dies.
她爸妈不在家 我15秒就能闯进去
Her parents aren't home. I can be in that room in 15 seconds.
要来个暖身题吗
You want a warmup question?
我不记得那些电影啦
I told you I don't know these movies!
问我知道的电影
Ask me about something I do know.
像是《灵病》和《宿怨》
Ask me about It Follows. Ask me about Hereditary.
还有《女巫》
Ask me about The Witch.
在第一部《惊声尖叫》中
In the first Stab movie,
哪个伍兹柏勒镇民成为电影系列主角
what Woodsboro native was introduced as the franchise's main character?
席妮皮斯考克
It's Sidney Prescott!
席妮皮斯考克 她住在榆树街
It's Sidney Prescott and she lived on Elm.
答对了 你很厉害啊
Correct. You see, you're gonna do great at this.
好了 第一题
Okay, question one…
我答对了 应该算数
No, I got that one right. It should count.
谁都能答对 只有上一集没有席妮
Anyone could have gotten that one right. Sidney's in every movie but the last one.
第一题
Question one:
《惊声尖叫》系列改编自谁写的书
Who wrote the original book that the Stab movies are based on?
电视上那个女的
The… The chick from TV!
电视上那个女的不算答案
"The chick from TV" is not gonna cut it, Tara.
盖儿魏德斯
Gale Weathers!
是盖儿魏德斯 王八蛋
It is Gale Weathers, you motherfucker!
答对了 安珀也许能活到日出
Correct. Amber might live to see the sunrise.
第二题 谁演第一集开场戏的蠢妞
Question two: Who played the dumb bitch in the beginning of Stab 1.
谁接了电话然后被凶手千刀万剐
who answers the phone and gets carved up by the killer?
去你的
Fuck you.
那是你的答案吗
Is that the answer you're going with?
没回答就算答错 时间不多了
A non-answer counts as a wrong answer, Tara.
时间快到了
Time's running out.
滴答…滴答…
Ticktock, ticktock, ticktock, ticktock…
海瑟葛拉罕
Heather Graham!
答对了 算你厉害
Correct! You pulled that one out.
最后一题
Now for the final question:
第一集的凶手是谁
Who was the killer in Stab 1?
我知道 你这烂咖
Oh, I know this one, you fuck.
是比利鲁米斯
It's Billy Loomis!
是比利鲁米斯 席妮的男友
It's Billy Loomis, and he was Sidney's boyfriend,
路克威尔逊演的
he was played by Luke Wilson,
我赢了 混蛋
and I got you, asshole!
我答对了
I got it! I got it right!
很抱歉 塔拉 你答错了
Oh, I'm sorry, Tara, but that's just not correct.
什么
What?
不 我答对了啊
No, no, it is. It is. That is right.
正确答案是比利鲁米斯和史都马克
The correct answer is Billy Loomis and Stu Macher.
第一集有两个凶手
There are two killers in the original Stab.
今晚有人会领便当了
I'm afraid someone's got to die now.
安珀 我来了
No, no, no. Amber, I'm coming.
靠
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
保全系统启动
All systems armed.
（警察来电）
警察正赶来 混蛋
The police are on their way, asshole!
保全系统解除
All systems disarmed.
（门已解锁）
保全系统启动
All systems armed.
- 保全系统解除 - 噢 天哪 不
- All systems disarmed. - Oh, my God. No.
保全系统启动
All systems armed.
保全系统解除 保全系统启动
All systems disarmed. All systems armed.
保全系统解除
All systems disarmed.
保全系统启动
All systems armed.
喂
Hello?
加分题 塔拉
Bonus question, Tara.
求你了
Please stop.
你在启动保全之前我能闯进你家吗
Do you think I made it inside your house before you could rearm?
救命啊
Help!
不要
No! No, no, no!
《惊声尖叫5》
（加州 莫德斯托）
小姐 请问一下
Excuse me, miss?
- 你刚吃了什么药 - 你的壮阳药
- What'd you just take? - Your boner pills.
这下你硬不起来了
Good luck getting it up now.
你…
You, um…
你就是我的壮阳药
You are my boner pills.
不好笑
No. No.
没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yes.
别老是担心我 我不是瓷娃娃
You don't have to check on me all the time. I'm not breakable.
我知道
Yeah, this I know.
（我是卫斯希克斯 记得吗）
（请尽快回电 是关于塔拉）
靠
Shit.
- 珊曼 - 嘿 怎么了
- Sam? - Hey. What's going on?
塔拉…遭到攻击
Uh, Tara… was attacked.
什么她…
What? Is she…
她还活着 但受了重伤
She's alive, but in bad shape.
她被…
She was…
刺伤
Stabbed.
- 刺伤 怎么会 - 她做了手术
医生说手术很成功
And the doctor said it went well.
她正在休养
She's resting now.
我知道你们闹翻了 但…
I know you guys aren't on the best terms, but…
我这就赶去
I'm on my way.
她不会有事 到时候见
She's gonna be okay, Sam. We'll see you soon.
- 等等 卫斯 - 什么事
- Hey, wait, Wes! - Yeah?
知道凶手是谁吗
Do they know who did this?
你最好还是来一趟
It's probably better if you just come here.
卫斯
Wes.
她说凶手戴着鬼脸面具
She said it was someone in a fucking Ghostface mask.
我妹受到攻击
My sister was attacked.
我得赶去
I gotta go.
等等 我跟你去
Wait, hey! Hey, hey hey. I'm… I'm going with you.
- 不 瑞奇 - 珊曼 我要跟你去
- No. No, Richie… - No, Sam. I'm coming with you.
- 好吧 - 好吧
- Okay. - Okay. Yeah.
各位同学 明天的课程和活动
Attention, Panthers. A reminder that all classes and school activities.
全都因为安全考量取消
are canceled tomorrow due to public safety concerns.
那是珊曼
That was Sam.
- 她要来 - 对
- She's coming? - Yeah.
等着看好戏吧
Watch everything get worse.
我只想说现在发生这种事
All I'm saying is, with everything going on right now,
我们的关系应该进入更亲密的阶段
I think it's time we take our relationship to the next, most intimate level.
他要我让他定位我的手机
He wants me to accept his Find My Fam request.
还没抓到凶手 这样才安全
It's the smartest option with a would-be killer on the loose.
我们都会知道对方在哪里
You know exactly where I am and I know exactly where you are.
好让你像吃醋男友跟踪我
Aw, you can stalk me like a jealous boyfriend.
你也可以跟踪我啊
And you can stalk me like a jealous boyfriend.
因为你们还没嘿咻吗
Is this because you two aren't having sex yet?
说得好 但我不是那种典型的球员
You bring up a very good point. Not that I want to sound like a stereotypical jock.
- 只想跟马子上床 - 好棒棒
- trying to get into his girl's pants… - Great!
别这么干 丽芙 有个变态杀手
Don't do it, Liv. There's a psycho out there.
你应该让自己更难被找到
You make yourself harder to find.
删除IG脸书 贴住手机镜头 关掉GPS
Delete social media, tape over your phone camera, disable GPS.
多谢你喔 史诺登
Yes, thank you very much, Edward Snowden.
你妈才刚为塔拉的案子问我话
Actually, your mother just interrogated me about Tara's attempted murder,
那超好玩的
which was very fun.
她每个人都问话 鬼脸杀手真的回来了
I'm sure she's asking everybody. I mean, Ghostface is back.
新闻还是没说是鬼脸杀手
The press still isn't saying Ghostface.
我妈不想引起集体恐慌
My mom doesn't want to cause a panic.
再发生命案就会传开来
It'll get out by the second or third killing.
天啊 敏蒂 塔拉还活着耶
Jesus, Mindy, there wasn't a first killing. Tara's alive.
- 那代表她还是可能会死 - 你在说什么
- Mmm. I mean, she could still die. - What the fuck?
凶手会回去杀她
Or the killer could come back for her.
靠拜托
Fuck! Mindy, come on.
准备防身用品 防狼喷雾剂和电击棒
I'm just telling you, arm up, okay? Pepper spray, check. Taser, check.
还有驱除女友剂
Girlfriend repellent, check.
水喔 谢啦
Nice. Thank you.
靠 那是…文斯吗
Holy shit. Is that… Vince?
你去年暑假勾搭上的变态
Wait. The creep you hooked up with last summer?
- 对啦 他跟我和塔拉一起打工 - 他和塔拉一起打工
- Yeah. He worked with me and Tara. - He worked with Tara?
他这几个礼拜都在追踪我的IG
He's been stalking my Instagram the last couple weeks,
贴一些超恶烂的留言
posting the creepiest shit.
我该好好扁他一顿
Probably time to introduce him to Hobbs and Shaw.
最好别在警长面前打架
Maybe not the best idea to incite violence right in front of the sheriff.
看来他要走了
Looks like he's leaving.
谢了 猛男
Thanks anyways, boys.
塔拉说她死命挣扎 你身上有瘀青
Hmm. Tara says she fought back hard. You've got bruises.
练球弄到的啦
It's from football practice.
- 最好是啦 - 塔拉醒了 她传讯给我
- Oh, sure. - Tara's awake. She just texted.
我要去医院 你们来吗
I'm going to the hospital. You guys coming?
- 好啊 - 好啊
- Yeah. - Yeah.
我不行 但晚点再见
Oh, uh… I can't, but I'll meet you guys there.
好吧
All right.
- 我没看过《惊声尖叫》 - 你从来没看过
- I've actually never seen Stab. - You've never seen Stab?
- 嗯 - 去年上映的那部也没有
- Mmm. - Not even the one that came out last year?
我也没看过《乱世佳人》
I've never seen Gone with the Wind either,
但我并不觉得自己不懂电影
but I don't consider it, like, a huge hole in my cinematic education.
《惊声尖叫》系列都是改编这里的事
Most of the Stab movies are based on things that happened here.
像是什么事
Define "things."
像是…
Things like…
比利鲁米斯和他麻吉戴着鬼脸面具
a guy named Billy Loomis and his friend carved up a bunch of high-school kids.
杀死一大堆高中生
while wearing this Halloween ghost mask.
就像《月光光心慌慌》
You mean like in Halloween?
- 不是啦 - 哦
- No. Not like in Halloween. - Oh.
- 听起来很像 - 好啦 是有点像
Sounds a lot like Halloween. - All right, it's a little like Halloween. - Okay.
每隔十年就有个猪头灵光一闪
And every decade or so, some idiot gets the bright idea.
戴上面具杀光朋友然后爆红
to put on the mask, kill his friends, and get famous too.
最后一次是2011年
The last time it happened was in 2011.
我们还自愿跑来
And we came here voluntarily?
我得确定塔拉没事
Well, I got to make sure Tara's okay.
当然啰
Right. Yes, of course.
我也得确定不会被疯子杀死
And I got to make sure we don't get sliced up by some lunatic.
他看了《黑色星期五》就想
who saw Friday the 13th and thought, "You know what?
那个杰森的杀人手法真的很赞
That Jason guy, he's got some pretty solid ideas."
（伍兹柏勒）
我能问个问题吗
Can I ask you one question though?
嗯
Yeah.
你知道为什么
Do you have any idea why.
那个戴着面具的人会想杀死你妹
someone wearing that mask would want to kill your sister?
不知道
No.
你还好吧
How are you feeling?
你来了
You came.
我当然会来
Of course I came.
这是我男友瑞奇
This is my boyfriend, Richie.
很高兴认识你 抱歉打扰了
It's so nice to meet you. I'm so sorry if I'm intruding.
我也很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you too.
嗨
Hi.
- 谢谢你打来 - 不客气
- Thank you for calling. - Of course.
你染了头发 我喜欢
Look at your hair! I like it.
这是双胞胎查德和敏蒂 还有卫斯
These are Chad and Mindy, the twins. And Wes.
我当过他们的保母
I used to babysit them all.
我一直都喜欢她这么说
Which is always how I like to be introduced.
还有安珀 嗨
And Amber. Hey.
嗨 见到你真好
Hi. Nice to see you.
- 嗨 我是瑞奇 - 嗨
- Hi. I'm Richie. - Hi.
- 妈妈呢 - 她在伦敦开会
Where's Mom? She's stuck at a conference in London.
刚才打过给我
She called me earlier.
只讲了十分钟
Yeah, for all of ten minutes.
塔拉累了 应该让她休息
Uh, look, guys, Tara's really tired. Maybe we should just give her some space.
珊曼 你别走
Not you, Sam.
我要你留下来
I want you to stay.
好
Okay.
- 我们都走吧 - 好喔
- But the rest. - Yeah.
你OK的话 我今晚可以睡这里
If it's okay with you, I could sleep here tonight.
这样很好
I'd really like that.
- 你有吸入器吧 - 有 没事的
- Do you have your extra inhaler? - I'll be fine.
好
Okay.
- 再见 - 宝贝 我就在外面 - 谢谢
- Bye. - Okay, I'll be right outside. - Thank you.
珊曼 我好害怕
Sam, I was so scared.
没事了
I know. It's okay.
她老姊是什么样的人
So what is she like, the sister?
珊曼珊曼超酷的
Sam? Oh, Sam is so cool.
那是因为她让你穿宝可梦睡衣
You only say that because she let you wear Pokemon onesies to bed for a year.
没错 一点也没错
True. That's a true statement.
才怪 珊曼一点都不酷
No, trust me. Sam is not cool.
她爸甩掉她妈 珊曼13岁 塔拉才8岁
Her dad left her mom, right? Walks right out when Tara's eight, Sam's 13.
珊曼开始变坏 被警察抓过几次
Sam started acting out, getting in trouble with the cops.
她一满18岁就一走了之
And then, on Sam's 18th birthday, she leaves.
像鬼一样消失
Ghosts them all.
也许她变了 我不想看到塔拉再伤心
Maybe Sam's changed. I just don't want to see Tara hurt again.
你要保护塔拉不被亲生姊姊伤害
So what, you're protecting Tara from her own sister now?
总得有人保护她吧
Well, someone has to.
男生都配不上她 她连家人也不准见
Okay, so no guys are good enough for her, and now her family's off-limits too?
杀人动机喔
Mmm, motive.
我得不到她 谁也别想
"If I can't have her, no one can."
- 什么 - 大家都知道你暗恋塔拉
What? We know you have a crush on Tara.
少来了 敏蒂
Okay. Come on, Mindy.
我们都有嫌疑
But we're all suspects.
- 除了丽芙 - 谢谢
- Except maybe Liv. - Thank you.
你太无趣不可能是变态
You're way too boring to be a psycho.
丽芙 想来杯烈酒吗
Yo, Liv. You want a real drink?
还是你想跟小屁孩一起混
Or are you happy sitting at this kids' table?
丑版的麦克迈尔斯 她去年只是玩玩
Listen up, uglier Michael Myers, it was a summer fling. It meant nothing.
- 我有跟你讲话吗 - 我才不管
- Was I talking to you? - I don't care who you're talking to.
- 丽芙 走吧 - 别跟她说话
- Liv, let's go. - Don't talk to her!
我不想听到你的声音
I don't want to hear your voice.
- 给我闭嘴 - 嘿
- Shut the fuck up. - Hey!
你再不滚我就报警
Get out of here or I'm calling the cops.
滚啊
Go!
- 回头见 宝贝 - 去你的
- I'll see you soon, sweetheart. - Hey, man, fuck you.
你们也一样 走吧
You kids too! Let's go!
看到没
Do you see this shit?
这间酒吧有够烂
Fuck this bar, man.
去它的
Fuck you. Fuck it!
搞什么
What the fuck?
是你吗 帅哥
Is that you, pretty boy? Huh?
给我滚出我的车
Get out of my fucking car!
嘿
Hey.
- 没事吧 - 没事
- You okay? - Yeah.
只是个恶梦
Just a bad dream.
你在看什么
What are you watching?
Netflix上的《惊声尖叫》
Oh, Stab is on Netflix.
干嘛我要有所准备
What? I want to be prepared.
我得去找东西吃
I got to go find something to eat.
好吧
Yeah, okay.
你好吗 珊曼
How you doing, Sam?
抗精神病药没有以前有效了
Mmm. Antipsychotics aren't working as well as they used to, are they?
去你的
Fuck you.
你不能逃避真正的自我
You can't run from who you are, Sam.
我只是想帮忙
I'm just trying to help.
你几时才会告诉她为什么发生这一切
Hey, when are you gonna tell her why all this is happening?
（安珀费里曼来电）
喂
Hello.
你好 珊曼莎
Hello, Samantha.
你是谁
Who is this?
知道你家庭小秘密的人
Someone who knows your little family secret.
你就是伤害我妹的混蛋
You're the fuck who hurt my sister?
我不只是要伤害她
Oh, she's not the only one I'm gonna hurt.
我总得想办法让你回来 对吧
I had to get you to come back here somehow, didn't I?
你想惹我 混蛋
You want to fuck with me, asshole?
我就在这儿 来找我啊
I'm right here. Come and get me.
我这就来
With pleasure.
救命
Help!
救命啊
Help! Help!
快来啊 他想杀我
Somebody help me! He's trying to kill me!
怎么了你没事了
What's going on? You're okay.
有人想在休息室杀我
Somebody tried to kill me in the break room!
酒吧外有具尸体 你又在这被攻击
I've got a body outside a bar on Main, and now you get attacked here.
你说是安珀打给你
You said the call came from Amber's number?
又怎样他也用我手机打给塔拉
So? We know he cloned my phone before when he attacked Tara.
或者 我只是猜的啦…你就是凶手
Or, and I'm just spit-balling here… you're the killer.
出事的时候你又在哪里
And where were you when all this happened?
我在…看Netflix
I was… watching Netflix.
- 超完美的不在场证明 - 你又在哪里
- Yeah. Super-solid alibi, bro. - So where were you?
我在警局讯问安珀和她的朋友
I was questioning her at the sheriff's station.
我听到消息就马上赶来
Yeah, I came as soon as I heard.
看Netflix的藉口也不错
But, you know, the Netflix alibi is good, too.
你们都别再说了
Both of you, stop it.
你会派更多警察保护她 对吧
You're gonna put more cops on her room, right?
没错
Yes.
我也能把你们转到私人楼层
And I can move you to a private floor.
副警长文森很尽职 你们会很安全
Deputy Vinson knows what he's doing. You'll be safe.
就像现在这样
Like we've been so far?
珊曼莎 我们出去聊聊
Samantha, let's step outside.
很高兴见到你 希克斯副警长
Nice to see you, Deputy Hicks.
- 好多有趣的回忆 - 是希克斯警长
- So many fun memories. - It's "Sheriff" Hicks.
我也记得你
I remember you too…
还有你为你家带来的麻烦
and all the trouble you used to cause your family.
你来这里没有帮助
Your presence here is not helping.
所以也许天一亮
So maybe when the sun comes up,
你和你男友就该上路
you and your boyfriend can hit the road.
让真正关心这社区的人处理这件事
and leave it to people who actually care about this community.
她还是这么讨喜
Well, she remains a delight.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
能不能出去一下我得跟塔拉谈谈
Um, would you mind giving us a second? I need to talk to Tara.
来吧 Netflix 走吧
Come on, Netflix. Let's go.
记得爸离开的事吗
Do you remember when Dad left?
记得一点
Parts, sure.
我才8岁 那重要吗
I was eight. I don't know what that has to do with anything.
非常重要
It has to do with it.
你记得…
Do you remember how…
妈放进阁楼的箱子吗
Mom used to keep those boxes up in the attic?
我上去过一次
Well, I was up there once,
我13岁那年去找圣诞礼物
when I was 13, looking for Christmas presents.
找到她在高中写的日记
And I found these old diaries that she kept from high school.
- 珊曼 到底是… - 听好
- Sam, what is… - Please.
我得告诉你
I just… I have to do this.
我找到一些旧日记
So I found these old diaries.
我知道不对 但还是偷看了
And I knew it was wrong, but I read some anyway.
因为妈在高中就怀了我
because Mom got pregnant with me in high school,
知道她和爸是怎么认识的会很酷
and I thought it could be cool to find out how she and Dad got together.
一定很浪漫
How romantic it must have been.
所以就偷看了日记
So I read some.
但一点都不浪漫
Only it wasn't romantic.
妈和爸在约会 但…
Mom was dating Dad, but…
她却爱上另一个家伙
she was in love with this other guy…
他害她怀孕
and he got her pregnant.
她跟爸说是他的 所以他就向她求婚
She told Dad it was his, and that's why he proposed senior year.
珊曼 你在说什么
Sam, what are you talking about?
我当时坐在阁楼
And I'm sitting there, in this attic,
才13岁
and I'm 13…
却发现我爸不是我的生父
and I just found out my dad isn't my dad.
于是我冲进妈的房间大吼大叫
So I go find Mom in her bedroom, and I'm screaming at her.
把日记丢到她脸上
and shoving this diary in her face,
根本就没发现
and I didn't even realize…
爸就站在我后面
that Dad was standing right behind me.
他被蒙在鼓里
He didn't know.
反而从我这里发现真相
He found out right then from me.
他那晚就离开
He left that night.
都是因为我
I'm the reason he left.
- 不 珊曼 - 妈从来没原谅我
- No, Sam… - Mom never forgave me.
而且你太小 她逼我永远不能说
Then she made me promise never to tell you because you were so young.
所以我才会变坏
And that's why I changed.
跟你的关系也越来越疏离
and I got distant and weird with you.
我跑出去混 开始嗑能拿到的每种药
And I went out and I started doing every drug that I could get my hands on.
直到我受不了 然后离开
until I couldn't take it anymore and I left town.
我不能继续在你身边
I just couldn't be around you anymore, Tara.
不只是因为我毁了这个家 也因为…
Not only because I destroyed our family that night, but because…
我从那些日记知道我的生父是谁
those diaries told me who my real father was.
是比利鲁米斯
It was Billy Loomis.
一定有人知道 所以才会伤害你
And somebody knows, and I think that's why you got hurt.
很抱歉我没告诉你 反而离家出走
And I'm so fucking sorry that I never told you and that I ran away.
- 真的很抱歉 - 出去
- I'm so sorry. - Get out.
塔拉
Tara.
你离开了五年
You're gone for five years…
整整五年
Five whole years.
我被刺伤你才回来
And then I get stabbed and you want to come back.
跟我说这一切
and drop all this shit on me?
- 我以为我在保护你 - 保护我什么
- I thought I was protecting you. - Protecting me from what?
知道真相
The truth?
不 我…拜托 塔拉
No, No, I… Please, Tara.
- 珊曼 - 给我滚出去 - 真的很抱歉
- Sam. - I need you to get the fuck out. - I'm so sorry.
- 珊曼 - 拜托
- Sam. - Please.
给我滚
Get the fuck out!
嘿 没事的 是我
Hey, hey. It's okay, it's me.
你在门外偷听吗
Were you listening at the door?
当然没有
No, no, of course not.
好啦 我有在偷听
Okay, yeah, I was listening at the door.
我生父是连环杀手…
It doesn't freak you out…
没有吓到你吗
that my real father was a serial killer?
老实说
I mean…
有啊
yeah.
我被吓死了
A great deal, yeah.
那就走吧 我能理解
Okay, well, then go. I get it.
但我要留下来揪出凶手
I just got to stay and figure it out.
我不会丢下你
I'm not leaving you here, Sam.
看恐怖片有时候会想
You know that part in horror movies.
对着角色大叫 学聪明点快逃
where you want to yell at the characters to be smart and get the fuck out?
就是这时候 瑞奇
This is that part, Richie.
你应该快逃走
You should get the fuck out.
我要留下来
But I'm staying.
我爱你
I love you.
- 你真是个蠢蛋 - 我是个蠢蛋
- You're such a dumbass. - I'm such a dumbass.
所以…
So…
你妹不跟你说话
your sister won't talk to you.
警方也不会帮忙
The police aren't gonna help.
下一步是什么
What's our next move?
去找一个专家
We go talk to an expert.
周二及周三温度降到摄氏10度
temperatures here Tuesday, Wednesday in the mid-50s,
下周则将回升到摄氏15度
and then finally we'll see those mid-60s returning next week.
一名当地少女在家中遭到扮成
Just one night after a local teen was attacked in her home.
鬼脸杀手的嫌犯攻击后一天
by an assailant wearing a Ghostface costume,
茱蒂希克斯警长公布 又发生两起攻击案
Sheriff Judy Hicks has now confirmed two more late-night attacks.
震惊伍兹柏勒小镇
that have left Woodsboro reeling.
第一名受害者文森史奈德
The first victim, Vincent Schneider,
在底袋撞球馆后遇害
was found dead behind the Corner Pocket Pool Hall.
第二名受害者
A second victim, as yet unnamed,
则是在伍兹柏勒综合医院内遇袭
was attacked inside Woodsboro General Hospital,
但她毫发无伤逃过一劫
but escaped without injuries.
今天伍兹柏勒镇民严阵以待…
Needless to say, Woodsboro is on high alert today…
来自洛克斐勒中心棚内直播
Live from Studio 1-A in Rockefeller Plaza…
早安 我是盖儿魏德斯
Good morning. I'm Gale Weathers.
节目开始之前 我想说个小故事
Before we dive in, I want to tell you a little story.
就发生在我来这里的路上
that happened on the way into the studio this morning.
我去超商买培根起司蛋三明治
I stopped to get a bacon… at a bodega, already a quintessentially New York…
走开
Go away!
抱歉打扰你 莱利先生
Sorry to bother you, Mr. Riley!
我们只想问你几个问题
We just want to ask you a few questions.
我不接受采访
I don't give interviews.
我们不是来采访你的
We're not looking for an interview.
你凭什么要我跟你说话
Give me one good reason why I should talk to you.
我是比利鲁米斯的女儿
I'm Billy Loomis's daughter.
那是个超烂的理由
That's a terrible reason for me to talk to you.
我叫珊曼莎卡本特
My name is Samantha Carpenter.
昨晚在医院受到攻击
I was attacked last night at the hospital.
我妹妹前晚被捅了七刀
The night before that, my sister was stabbed seven times.
你一定知道那种感觉
I know you know what that's like.
我只想保护我家人
I'm just trying to protect my family.
我只求你给我五分钟
Five minutes. That's all I'm asking.
我给你两分钟
I'll give you two minutes.
我正在看节目
I'm missing a show I like.
要是我想留浏海 拜托阻止我
bangs again, stage an intervention.
盖儿魏德斯
Gale Weathers.
- 你们不是… - 是啊
- Weren't you two, um… - Yeah.
他是谁
Who's he?
这是我男友瑞奇
Oh, this is Richie, my boyfriend.
你认识他多久
How long have you known him?
半年
Six months?
他一开始就知道你爸是谁吗
Did he know who your dad was when you met?
对伍兹柏勒镇或鬼脸杀手感兴趣
Express any interest in Woodsboro or the Ghostface killings?
你在胡说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
凶手很迷《惊声尖叫》 对吧
Your killer's obsessed with the Stab movies, right?
《惊声尖叫》系列电影有一些生存法则
Well, there are certain rules to surviving a Stab movie.
相信我 我知道
Believe me, I know.
第一条法则
Rule number one:
绝对不能信任恋爱对象
Never trust the love interest.
表面上看来细心体贴又可靠
They seem sweet, caring, supportive. Then welcome to act 3,
到了第三幕就会想杀了你
where they're trying to rip your head off.
塔拉遇袭时我和珊曼在莫德斯托
I was with Sam in Modesto when Tara was attacked.
让我猜 她在医院被攻击
And let me guess, you were just in the other room,
你刚好在另一个房间却没人能证实
conveniently unaccounted for when she was attacked at the hospital.
我得让这个邋遢大叔羞辱我吗
Okay, do I have to take this from shitty Sam Elliott over here, or what?
第二条法则
Rule number two…
凶手的动机一定和过去有关联
the killer's motive is always connected to something in the past.
- 我是比利的女儿 - 对
- I'm related to Billy. - Right,
但为何要杀死路人甲文斯
but then why kill that random Vince guy?
你们得自己查清楚
That's for you to figure out.
第三条也是最重要的法则
And rule number three, and this is the most important rule:
凶手一定在第一名受害者的朋友圈
The first victim always has a friend group that the killer is a part of.
你妹妹有要好的朋友圈吗
Does your sister have a close-knit group of friends?
有啊
Yeah.
她真的有
She does.
其中一个就是凶手
Then look for the killer there.
查出凶手犯案的动机
If you can find out why they're doing this,
就会知道下一个是谁
you can figure out who's next.
那就帮助我们
So help us.
帮我们揪出幕后凶手
Help us figure out who is behind this.
开什么玩笑我被捅了九刀
You kidding me? I've been stabbed nine times.
神经严重受损 还有只跛脚
I've got permanent nerve damage and a fun little limp.
你觉得我想再来一次
You think I want to do that again?
你说一定和过去有关联 对吧
You just said it always goes back to the past, right?
如果我有危险…
So if I'm in danger…
就代表你也一样
that means you're in danger.
拜托
Come on.
让我们携手合作
Let's do this together.
时间到了
Your time's up.
天啊
Jesus!
他在电影里比较好玩
Yeah, he's way more fun in the movies.
好吧 现在要怎样
Okay, uh, what's next?
朋友圈
The friends.
多谢了 凯文
Thanks so much for that, Kevin.
气象报告后
Coming up after our local weather,
要谈谈和老朋友重聚的好与坏
the pros and cons of reuniting with old friends.
喂
Hello?
席妮 是我
Hey, Sid, it's me.
杜威
Dewey?
天啊 有多久了
Oh, my God. How long has it been?
我趁送女儿上学前正在跑步
I'm just trying to get a run in before I take the girls to school.
你好吗
How are you?
很好 真的很好
I'm good, really good.
你呢马克好吗
How are you? How's Mark?
我会留住他
I think I'll keep him.
警长当得怎样
How are things in the sheriff's business?
呃 其实…
Uh, they're…
- 还不错 - 最近联络过盖儿吗
- They're fine. But, Sid… - Have you talked to Gale lately?
两年多没联络了
No. Not in a couple years.
我知道你们离婚了 但…
I know things didn't end well with you guys, but…
席妮
Sid…
又开始了
it's happening again.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
戴着鬼脸面具的凶手
Some idiot in a Ghostface mask.
目前有三人遇害 一人丧命
Three attacks so far. One dead.
这次感觉不太一样
Something about this one just feels different.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事 你知道我的
I'm fine, you know me.
是啊
Yeah.
我知道 所以才会问
I do. That's why I'm asking.
我没事
I'm fine.
只是…
I just…
希望你安全 你有枪吗
want you to be safe up there. Do you have a gun?
我是席妮皮斯考克 我当然有枪
I'm Sidney fucking Prescott. Of course I have a gun.
那就好
Good. That's good.
盖儿知道吗
Does Gale know?
我待会就打给她
No, she's my next call.
但你要答应我
But, Sid, promise me:
不管你听到或看到什么新闻 千万别来
No matter what you hear or what you see on the news, don't come here.
别介意 但我不会再去那个小镇
No offense, Dewey. I have no intention of ever setting foot in that town again.
很好
Good.
杜威
Dewey…
不管凶手想杀谁 你一定能保护他们
whoever this killer's after, I'm glad they have you to protect them.
注意安全 好吗
But… you be safe, okay?
我会的
Will do.
很高兴听到你声音
It's good to hear your voice.
我也是 席妮
You too, Sid.
加油 振作点 杜威
Come on. Get it together, Dewey.
（盖儿）
（鬼脸回来了 别来这里）
（希望你一切安好）
大概不应该传笑脸的
Probably shouldn't have sent the smiley face.
（我还是）
哇靠 他来了
Holy shit. He came.
我决定暂时协助你们调查
I've decided to temporarily assist you in your investigation.
谢谢你
Thank you.
那家伙洗了澡不代表他应该配枪
Look, just because that guy showered doesn't mean he should have a gun.
（蓝迪米克斯纪念家庭剧院）
你怎么对《惊声尖叫》这么熟
How do you know so much about the Stab movies?
家族遗传
Runs in her family.
蓝迪是我们的舅舅
Randy was our uncle.
安息吧
RIP.
你叫我把大家都找来
You said to bring everybody.
哇 嫌疑犯
Ooh, suspects!
我哥会很骄傲
My brother would be so proud.
嗨 玛莎
Hey, Martha.
杜威嗨
Dewey! Hi!
你看起来…
You look…
是啊
Yeah.
- 老婆好吗 - 妈 可以了啦 谢谢
How's the wife? Mom, we're good. Thank you.
好吧 玩得开心
All right, kids, have fun.
我请敏蒂把大家找来是因为…
I asked Mindy to call everybody here, because…
我有件事要告诉你们
there's something I have to tell you.
让我搞清楚
Let me get this straight.
你是比利鲁米斯的女儿
You're saying that you're the daughter of Billy Loomis,
我们其中一个是凶手
and, what, that one of us is the killer?
凶手说他知道我的秘密
The killer told me he knew my secret.
他为了让我回来才攻击塔拉
He attacked Tara to lure me back here.
他干嘛又马上杀死跟踪丽芙的烂咖
But then why immediately go and murder some douche-nozzle that was stalking Liv?
为什么是我们其中一个
And why does it have to be one of us?
杜威警长呢也许他是凶手
What about Deputy Dewey here? Maybe he's the killer.
别介意喔
No offense.
不会 我的动机是什么
None taken, but what's my motive?
你被捅了N次
You got stabbed a billion times,
被出名老婆狠甩 然后开始酗酒
got dumped by your famous wife and crawled into a bottle.
你肯定有嫌疑
I think it's safe to say you're on the suspect list.
也许你才是凶手
Well, maybe you're the killer.
因为你很会伤人
Because that cut deep.
那个烂咖也有关联
That douche-nozzle is connected.
我估狗过 他妈是莱丝莉马克
I googled him. His mom is Leslie Macher.
- 史都马克的妹妹 - 史都马克是谁
- Stu Macher's sister. - Who's Stu Macher?
比利鲁米斯的共犯
He's Billy Loomis's accomplice.
真正的疯子
A real loony tune.
好吧
Okay. Okay.
前三个受害者都跟原来的凶手有关联
So the first three attacks are all on people related to the original killers.
天啊 他在拍重启续集
Oh, my God. He's making a requel!
什么
A what?
或是传承续集 粉丝有不同说法
Or a legacyquel. Fans are torn on the terminology.
拜托讲白话
Please speak English.
记得去年的《惊声尖叫》续集吗
Remember the Stab movie that came out last year?
对耶 《锋回路转》的导演导的嘛
Oh, yeah! The one the Knives Out guy directed?
我蛮喜欢那部电影的
I actually really liked that one.
当然啰 你的品味很差
Of course you did. You have terrible taste.
我恨你
I hate you.
《惊声尖叫》的铁粉超讨厌的
The point is, the hard-core Stab fans hated it.
只要上滴卡电影板
You go on 4chan and Dreadit,
大家都说《惊声尖叫8》毁了童年回忆
all they're talking about is how Stab 8 pissed on their childhoods.
为了更有深度硬要探讨社会议题
How they crammed in social commentary just to elevate it.
女主角也是个玛丽苏
How the main character's a Mary Sue.
- 玛丽苏是什么 - 你不会想知道
- What's a Mary Sue? - You really don't want to know.
高级恐怖片有什么不好
What's wrong with elevated horror?
乔登皮尔超屌的
I mean, Jordan Peele fucking rules.
那还用说 但那不是《惊声尖叫》
Uh, obviously, but that's not Stab.
《惊声尖叫》只是部后设砍杀恐怖片
Real Stab movies are meta slasher whodunits, full stop.
- 拜托 那只是部电影 - 才不是
- Come on. It's just a movie. - No, it's not.
有些人觉得第一集是经典名片
To some people, the original is their favorite thing in the world.
让他们爱上恐怖片
The movie that made them love horror.
他们才十岁就看过 有共通的话题
That Mom or Dad showed them when they were ten that bonded them together.
谁敢侮辱那个回忆就会被骂翻
And God help anyone who slightly fucks with that special memory.
更痛恨不尊重原版的作品
Who makes a movie they think disrespects it.
看来凶手在拍自己的《惊声尖叫8》
It sounds like our killer is writing his own version of Stab 8,
不过是一部重启续集
but doing it as a requel.
什么意思
Which is?
不能只是重启一个电影系列
See, you can't just reboot a franchise from scratch anymore.
不然会被酸民出征
The fans won't stand for it.
黑色圣诞节 鬼娃恰吉 别闯阴阳界
Black Christmas, Child's Play, Flatliners…
那种拍法很母汤
That shit doesn't work.
但也不能直接拍续集
But you can't just do a straight sequel, either.
必须要有新的创意
You got to build something new.
但也不能太新 粉丝会暴动
But not too new, or the Internet goes bug-fucking nuts.
必须延续既有的故事线
It got to be part of an ongoing story line,
就算故事早就结束了
even if the story shouldn't have been ongoing in the first place.
可以有全新主角
New main characters, yes,
但是要找回原版经典角色
but supported by and related to legacy characters.
不算重启 也不是续集
Not quite a reboot, not quite a sequel.
就像《月光光心慌慌》、《夺魂锯》
Like the new Halloween, Saw,
《魔鬼终结者》、《侏罗纪公园》、《魔鬼克星》
Terminator, Jurassic Park, Ghostbusters…
甚至《星际大战》
fuck, even Star Wars!
一定都要回溯到原版的电影
It always, always goes back to the original!
你是说我变成同人小说中的小角色
Are you telling me that I'm caught in the middle of fan-fucking-fiction?
你不只是小角色 珊曼
Not just in the middle, Sam.
你是主角
You're the star.
你别说得太复杂
So, not to put too fine a point on it,
但根据重启续集的规则
but, according to requel rules…
下一个是谁
who's next?
按照故事模式
Going by the pattern,
下一个跟之前的角色一定有关联
whoever it is has to be connected to someone that came before.
我开始后悔来这里了
I'm starting to regret coming here.
我妈也是其中一个角色
Jesus, my mom was a character in one of them.
没人鸟那些烂续集 卫斯 你很安全
No one cares about the shitty inferior sequels, Wes. You're safe.
但蓝迪是舅舅 你跟我死定了
With Randy as our uncle, though, you and I are probably screwed.
- 等等 什么 - 或者你就是凶手
- Wait. What? - Or you're the killer,
为了替自己洗白才在这里练肖话
and this whole elaborate monologue is just to cover your tracks.
凶手是谁已经很明显了
I think it's pretty clear who the killer is at this point.
是谁
Who?
你
You.
完全符合重启续集的逻辑
It makes perfect requel sense.
- 是很合理 - 是啊
- That actually does make sense. - Yeah.
太扯了
Fuck this.
- 我回饭店等你 - 等等
- Meet you back at the motel. - Sam, wait.
珊曼 等等
Sam, wait.
恐怖片的第一条法则是别分开
The first fucking rule of these movies is don't split up!
她真是个呛妞 对吧
The nerve of that girl, right?
我现在没这个心情
Really not in the mood right now.
珊曼
Sam, Sam, Sam.
凶手还在逍遥法外
There is a killer on the loose.
他想杀你和你妹妹
He's threatening you. He's threatening your sister.
你要像以前一样逃避自我
Are you gonna run away from who you are like you always do,
还是要善用它
or are you gonna use it?
我跟你不一样
I'm not like you.
真的吗
Really?
那你要怎么活下去
Then how else are you gonna survive?
接受真正的你 揪出真正的凶手
I say accept who you are, let's get out there, find out who's doing this,
大开杀戒吧
and cut some fucking throats!
不
No!
多点一份毛豆
Mmm. And extra edamame. Please.
谢谢 我十分钟就到
Thank you. I'll be there in ten minutes.
掰
Bye.
小子 是你吗
That you, tiger?
天啊
Jesus!
你有没有注意安全
Are you being safe out there, honey?
有啦 我朋友都在笑我
To the point that all my friends mock me, yes.
这样才乖
Good boy.
- 晚饭吃什么 - 寿司 我正要去拿
What's for dinner? Sushi. I was just leaving to pick it up.
怎么不叫外送
Oh. Why don't you just Postmates it?
送来就不新鲜了
Oh, it gets all smooshy by the time it's here.
我知道你不喜欢
I know you hate that.
- 去洗澡 我很快就回来 - 好的
- Go shower. I'll be back soon. - Okay.
- 帮我放回去 - 好
- Can you put this away for me? - Yes.
- 爱你唷 - 爱你
- Love you. - Love you.
- 记得锁门 - 我会啦
- Lock the door. - I will.
（未知来电）
- 希克斯警长 - 你好 茱蒂警长
Sheriff Hicks. Hello, Sheriff Judy.
- 你是谁 - 你应该知道
- Who is this? - I think you know.
我最爱恐怖片 还有刀子
I'm a fan of scary movies. And knives.
你最喜欢的恐怖片是什么
What's your favorite scary movie?
我比较喜欢动画片和歌舞片
I prefer animated films and musicals.
你为什么要杀人
Why are you doing this?
我会全盘托出 我是打来自首的
I'll tell you all about it. I'm calling to turn myself in.
好主意
I think that's a great idea.
（凶手来电 追踪电话）
We'll sit down at the station,
我会说出为什么要杀死那两个人
and I'll tell you about the two people I've killed.
你只杀死了一个人
You've only killed one person.
等我见到你 你的宝贝儿子早就没命了
By the time I see you, I'll have gutted your baby boy.
去你的
Fuck you!
（卫斯）
快接啊 卫斯
Pick up, Wes!
（妈妈来电）
这是希克斯警长 立刻赶去我家
This is Sheriff Hicks. I need units to converge on my house ASAP.
收到 马上去
Copy that. We're on it.
连络不到他 对吧
Can't get him on the phone, can you?
他一定在忙
He must be busy.
我怎么知道你在他附近
How do I know you're anywhere near him?
看过《惊魂记》吗
Ever seen the movie Psycho?
求求你
Please…
别伤害我儿子
don't hurt my boy.
为什么
Why not?
- 他是个好孩子 - 是吗
- He's a good kid. - Is he, now?
从来没伤害过人
He never hurt anyone.
那还不够好
That's not enough.
求求你 要我做什么都行
Please! I'll do anything!
你赶不回去的 茱蒂警长
You're not gonna make it in time, Sheriff Judy.
卫斯
Wes!
我来了
I'm coming!
卫斯
Wes!
救命啊
Help!
（未接来电 妈妈）
（冰箱里有柠檬冰块）
妈
Mom?
去…你的
Fuck… you!
小姐 你不能进来
Miss, you can't be here. You can't be here.
抱歉 我认识她儿子
No, I'm sorry. I know her son.
- 她儿子卫斯… - 很抱歉
- Her son, Wes. Is he… - I'm sorry.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
你是…
You're…
你是你
Well, you're you.
是我没错啊
Last time I checked.
没事吧你好像很难过
Are you okay? You seem like you're having a bit of a moment.
你认识警长吗
Did you know the sheriff?
算是吧
Sort of.
她不太喜欢我
She didn't like me very much.
她也不喜欢我
She didn't like me either.
我是珊曼莎 珊曼卡本特
Um… I'm Samantha. Sam. Carpenter.
我和我妹被攻击
My sister and I were attacked.
真的很抱歉
Oh. Sorry to hear that.
我是盖儿…
I'm Gale…
莱利
Riley.
魏德斯 我是盖儿魏德斯 失陪
Weathers. I'm Gale Weathers. Excuse me.
- 盖儿 - 一则简讯
Gale? - A text? - Ow.
你传简讯告诉我凶手回来了
You tell me the killer is back in a text?
- 很痛耶 - 活该
- Ow, that hurts. - Good!
- 你在上节目 - 你怎么知道
- You were on the air. - How do you know?
直觉吧
A hunch.
你的气色不错 还在写书吗
You look good. Are you still writing?
没时间
No time.
你写书的时候最开心
You were always happiest when you were writing.
抗拒不了耸动新闻 对吧
Couldn't resist a good story, could you?
别这么脑残 我是担心你才会来
Don't be an idiot, Dewey. I'm here because I was worried about you.
好啦 制作人当然要我报导这新闻
Okay, yes. My producers wanted me to cover this, for obvious reasons,
但有九成是因为你
but 90% is because of you.
我感觉有九成好多了
Well, I feel 90% better.
别这么玻璃心
Don't be so sensitive.
你几时关心过我的心情
Since when did you care about my feelings?
尤其是这两年
Especially not in the last couple years.
听好 别假装是我要离婚的
All right, listen. Let's not pretend I'm the one who ended things.
没人在假装 我记得是怎么回事
No one's pretending, Gale. I remember what happened.
你为什么没穿制服
Why aren't you in uniform?
我退休了
I retired.
什么时候
Since when?
他们要我退休的时候
Since they asked me to.
噢 杜威
Oh, Dewey.
我不需要你可怜我 盖儿
I don't need your pity, Gale.
我做了选择 你也一样
I made my choices. So did you.
也该轮到我了 那是个好机会
It was my turn. It was a great opportunity.
- 你说会试试看 - 我试过啦
- You said you'd try. - And I did.
才两个月
For two whole months!
如果你想让我更内疚 祝好运
Listen, if you want to make me feel worse than I already do, good luck.
早上还不错 我能看你的节目
The mornings aren't so bad, 'cause I get to see you.
假装我还在纽约
Pretend I'm still back there in New York.
然后才想起来…
But then I remember…
我受不了 才会半夜走人
that I couldn't hack it. I left in the middle of the night…
像个孬种
like a coward.
你当时为什么不说
Why wouldn't you tell me that then?
我会想办法的
It would have mattered.
你有很多缺点 杜威
You are a lot of things, Dewey…
但绝不是孬种
but you are not a coward.
你只是…
You just…
注定要待在伍兹柏勒
You just were meant to be in Woodsboro.
难道你不是
And you weren't?
向我保证你会尽快离开
Promise me you'll leave as soon as you can.
你知道我不能保证
You know I can't promise that.
我为茱蒂的死感到遗憾
I'm sorry about Judy.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
但她会是你下一本书精彩的一章
But she'll make a great chapter in your next book.
更别说鬼脸杀手全新的招牌凶器
And don't even get me started on Ghostface's signature new weapon.
真的超猛的
That shit is lit.
为什么要用《惊声尖叫》一样的片名
And can we talk about the title? Stab?
明明是《惊声尖叫8》 你骗不了人
Just call it Stab 8. It's fucking Stab 8. You're not fooling anyone.
太扯了
It's such bullsh…
- 你在哪没事吧 - 没事
Where have you been? You okay? Yeah, I'm fine.
敏蒂没在唬烂 《惊声尖叫8》不一样
That Mindy girl wasn't kidding. Stab 8 is not like the others.
跟其他电影无关 没有经典角色
I mean, no connection to the other movies. No legacy characters at all. Richie.
这个电影系列从第五集就走歪了
If you ask me, this franchise goes off the rails with number five.
听好 他又杀死两个人 卫斯和他妈妈
Richie, listen to me. He killed two more people. Wes and his mother.
他杀死警长这么厉害
He killed the sheriff? You can do that?
你没事吧你在哪
I mean, are you okay? Where are you?
- 我再打给你 - 不 珊曼…
- I'll call you right back. - No, Sam…
谁在医院
Who's at the hospital?
谁在保护我妹
Who's watching my sister?
我才刚得知警长的事
I just heard about the sheriff.
这里需要我
They needed me here!
- 你要去哪 - 我妹有危险
- Where are you going? - My sister's in trouble!
…茱蒂希克斯惨遭杀害
where Judy Hicks has just been brutally murdered.
你还在等什么开车啊
What are you waiting for? Drive!
快啊 走啊
Come on. Let's go!
有人吗
Hello?
管它的
Fuck this.
靠
Fuck!
（珊曼来电）
可恶
Goddamn it!
你该边开车边打电话吗
Should you really be making a phone call right now?
快接
Please, please.
停车你知道我们得活着才能救她 对吧
Stop! You know we have to live through this to help her, right?
坐好了
Just hold on.
糟了
Holy shit.
- 该死的 - 瑞奇
- Goddamn it! - Richie?
你在这里干嘛
What are you doing here?
珊曼打来 她说…
Sam called. She said that…
你可能有危险
you were in trouble.
- 你用手机K我 - 小心
- Did you hit me with the phone? - Look out!
瑞奇
Richie!
- 你在医院吗 - 你好 珊曼莎
- Are you at the hospital? - Hello, Samantha.
瑞奇现在不能接电话
Richie can't come to the phone right now.
他会知道随便乱入
He's finding out what happens to people.
多管闲事的人有什么下场
who stick their noses in business that doesn't concern them.
- 别伤害他 - 这样吧 我让你选择
- Please don't hurt him. - Tell you what. You can choose.
我只杀一个人
I'll only kill one.
什么塔拉
What? What? Tera!
你想听到谁死
Who do you want to hear die?
不 求求你 别伤害他们
No. Please! I'm begging you. Please don't hurt them.
真假你不想救自己的妹妹
Really? You can't save your own sister?
你只要说 杀死瑞奇
All you have to do is say, "Kill Richie."
不
No!
塔拉别碰她
Tara! Don't touch her!
求求你
Please, please, please. I'm begging you.
或是说 杀死塔拉
Or say, "Kill Tara, "
我就会用力捅上次没捅到的器官
and I'll make sure to hit all the organs I missed last time.
- 不 - 去你的
- No! - Fuck you!
求求你 别伤害她
I'm begging you. Please don't hurt her.
最后一次机会 选择吧
Last chance to save one. Choose!
你为什么这么做
Why are you doing this?
你想知道原因
You want to know why, Sam?
也许是因为你是自私的贱货
Maybe it's because you're a selfish bitch.
连决定要救你爱的人都没办法
who can't even make a decision to save the life of someone you love.
也许你在这个电影系列太弱了
Maybe you're too weak for this franchise.
也许你说的对
Maybe you're right.
也许我只是在拖延时间 猪头
Or maybe I'm just stalling for time, fuckhead.
我去帮瑞奇
I'll get Richie.
塔拉
Tara!
天哪
Oh, my God!
来吧 瑞奇
Come on.
没事了 我扶你
It's okay. I got you.
不会有事的
It's gonna be all right.
快进电梯
Get the elevator!
我今天不会死
Not today.
瑞奇
Richie.
我们快闪吧
Let's get out here.
- 来吧 快点 - 噢
- Come on, hurry up. - Oh!
- 头部 - 什么
- The head. - What?
要打爆头 不然凶手一定会回来
You have to shoot 'em in the head, or they always come back.
杜威 谁会管这么多
Dewey! Who gives a fuck?
- 我会 - 不杜威
- I do. - No! Dewey!
你今天死定了
Yes, today.
（盖儿来电）
这是我的荣幸
It's an honor.
不
No!
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我跟他不熟 但…
I didn't know him well, but…
他帮助过我
he helped me.
他就是这种人
That's what he did.
总是在帮助别人
He helped people.
我应该拦住他
I should've stopped him.
这样一来我妹就会死
If you had, my sister would be dead.
珊曼莎 你妹妹醒了
Samantha, your sister's awake.
盖儿
Gale.
席妮
Sidney.
我一听说就赶来了
I came as soon as I heard.
很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
你不该来的
You shouldn't be here.
你也不该来
You shouldn't be here either.
- 马克和孩子们呢 - 他们很安全
- Mark and the kids are okay? - Yeah, they're safe for now.
我就是来做个了结
I'm here to make sure of that.
过来
Come here.
你还好吧
How you feeling?
我每次遇袭都会有更好的止痛药
Every time I get attacked, they give me better painkillers.
那还不错
So there's that.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
干嘛抱歉你救了我
For what? You saved my life.
我应该早点告诉你
For not telling you sooner.
我是爸离开的原因
For being the reason Dad left.
你不是爸离开的原因
You're not the reason Dad left.
你不能选择你来自哪或是谁的女儿
You didn't choose where you came from. Or who you came from.
我并不怪你
I don't blame you for that.
只怪你也离开我
I blame you for leaving me too.
我不会再离开你了
That's never gonna happen again.
我知道
I know.
你当时为什么不告诉我
But why didn't you come to me back then?
我可以帮忙
I could've helped.
因为…
Because…
我很害怕
I was scared.
怕什么
Of what?
我怕会变得跟他一样
I was scared that I would turn out just like him.
所以才会逃走
So I ran.
为了保护你
To protect you.
- 不被我伤害 - 珊曼…
- From me. - Sam…
你永远都不会跟他一样
you could never be like him.
- 你现在很嗨 - 我超嗨的
- You're so high right now. - I'm so high right now.
我都懒得骗你
I'm not even gonna lie.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
现在要怎么做
So what do we do now?
做遇到这种情况没人做过的事
What nobody ever does in these situations.
立刻离开伍兹柏勒
We're gonna get the fuck out of Woodsboro.
- 那是她 - 对
- That's her? - Yeah.
珊曼莎
Samantha?
叫我珊曼
It's Sam.
- 我是… - 我知道你是谁
- I'm… - I know who you are.
希望你没事
I hope you're okay.
- 很抱歉… - 你是比利的女儿
- Listen, I'm sorry… - You're Billy's daughter.
我去把车开过来
We'll bring the car around.
对 我是他的女儿
Yeah. I'm his daughter.
抱歉让你觉得不舒服
I'm sorry if that's weird for you.
不会的 只是…
No, no, it's…
我经历过这种事 很多次
I've been through this. A lot.
想谈谈吗
You want to talk?
谢谢你
I appreciate it.
我也…
And I'm…
很遗憾杜威死了
I'm really sorry about Dewey.
但我要带我妹远离这一切
But I'm taking my sister away from all this.
我也逃跑过 没有用 凶手一定会跟来
I tried running too. It doesn't work, it always follows.
恕我直言 那是你 不是我
All due respect, that's your life, not mine.
- 没这么简单 - 你要我怎样 大妈
- I'm not so sure about that. - What do you want from me, lady?
别这么毒舌 呛妞
Hey! Watch your tone, new girl.
凶手一定和原版角色有关
You know how they always say it goes back to the original?
就是我们
Here's the original.
我需要你帮忙
I want your help.
因为你错了 这也与你有关
Because you're wrong, this is your life now.
这代表凶手会一直追杀你
Which means whoever this is will keep coming for you.
- 所以呢 - 我要你帮我们杀死他
- So? - So I want you to help us kill him.
你要我帮你和晨间节目主播杀人
You want me to help you and the host of a morning show commit murder?
- 没错 - 是啊
- Correct. - Yeah.
我要扮演什么角色
And I'm what in this scenario?
诱饵无助受害者
The bait? The helpless victim?
- 适合的话… - 你并不无助
- If the shoe fits… - You're not helpless, Sam.
他杀死你的和我们的朋友
He killed your friend, he killed ours.
我有小孩 他一天不死我就一天睡不着
And I have kids, which means I won't sleep until he's in the ground.
很抱歉这危害到你们的生活
Look, I'm sorry about what this has done to your lives.
但不管你们或任何人怎么说
But no matter what you or the killer or anyone says,
这不是我的故事
this isn't my story.
好吧 咱们快闪吧
All right! Let's get the fuck out of town, huh?
抱歉 那是我男友瑞奇
Sorry. That's my boyfriend, Richie.
很高兴见到…我们见过面
Nice to meet… We met.
快上车 永远别再见到这些人
Sam, please get in the car so we never have to see these people again.
- 珊曼… - 不 我们要离开
- Sam… - No. We're leaving.
只有这样才能保护塔拉
That's the only way I can protect Tara.
好吧 祝好运
Okay, good luck.
你也是
You too.
我们被她打脸了
Well, that went fucking horribly.
放心 我有计划 她是个悍妞
Don't worry, I have a plan. She seems really tough.
老实说 她再悍也没用
Honestly, Sid, who gives a shit?
你自己也说凶手会追杀她
You said it yourself, he's gonna go after her.
我在她车上放了追踪器
I put a tracker on her car.
什么
You did what?
这是盖儿魏德斯会做的事
It seemed like something Gale Weathers would do.
这算是赞美啰
Take that as a compliment.
（离开伍兹柏勒）
我留言给妈 说我们要去哪
I left a message for Mom. I told her where we're going.
你还好吧
You good back there?
靠 在哪里
Fuck, where is it?
什么东西
Where's what?
我的吸入器 我都有备用的
My inhaler. I usually keep an extra one.
应该回去吗
Should we go back?
我才不想回去那间杀人医院
Whoa. Okay. I vote for not going back to the murder hospital.
- 去药局呢 - 我需要处方笺
- You want to stop at a pharmacy? - I'd need a prescription.
安珀家有一个 我们会路过
But I left an extra one at Amber's. Her house is on the way.
不 不行
No. No. No, no, no.
我很快就出来
I'd be in and out.
你能撑到莫德斯托吗
Could you hold out till Modesto?
- 不能 - 地址是什么
- I don't think so. - Okay, what's the address?
别肖想路123号
123 No Fucking Way Lane.
瑞奇 她很需要
Richie, she needs it.
我也需要活下去 你也是
And I need to keep all the blood inside my body. So do you.
瑞奇 拜托
Richie, please.
没事的
It's okay.
好吧 靠 地址是什么
Okay, yeah. Fuck. What's the goddamn address?
嘿 多谢光临
Hey, thank you for coming.
（纪念卫斯）
倒好倒满 谢谢
Keep pouring, Wheeler. Thank you.
敬卫斯
To Wes! To Wes!
暖男一枚
Beautiful son of a bitch.
爱你唷
We love you, buddy!
灌酒 真假这是追悼会
Shots, really? This is supposed to be a memorial.
这是我追悼的方法
Well, this is how I mourn.
顺便忘掉死神随时会降临的事实
and distract myself from the looming specter of Death.
嘿 啤酒快没了
Hey, we're low on beer.
地下室还有 我去拿
There's more in the basement. I'll go get some.
搞什么鬼 敏蒂天啊
What the fuck, Mindy? Jesus!
那是考验 你失败了
That was a test. And you failed.
有面具杀手在 不能单独行动
Never go off on your own with a masked killer around.
明明是你说要更多啤酒
You're the one that said we needed more beer.
你应该叫我跟你来
And you should have asked me to come with you.
你知道有面具杀手在还不能做什么吗
You know what else you shouldn't do when there's a masked killer around?
什么
What?
单独跟着别人到阴森恐怖的地下室
Follow someone into a dark, creepy basement alone.
说真的…
I mean…
你怎知我不是凶手
how do you know I'm not the killer?
因为我才是
Because I am.
我并不是啦
I'm not, actually.
不过这是个教训 别相信任何人
But let that be a lesson. Don't trust anyone.
那我怎么能相信你不是凶手
Then how can I trust you when you say you're not the killer?
一点也没错
Exactly.
你学得很快
You're learning.
回到楼上吧
Now let's go back upstairs.
你先走
You first.
聪明喔
Very good.
我准备好了
I think… Think I'm ready.
我们应该嘿咻
I mean, I think we should.
就是现在 想去楼上吗
Like now. You want to go upstairs?
去楼上
Like… Like upstairs?
嘿啊 现在
Uh-huh. Right now.
别误会喔 但还是不要比较好
Don't take this the wrong way, but I think I have to pass on that.
什么
What?
为什么
Why?
你知道的 我不能完全确定你不是…
You know, I'm not like entirely sure that you're not the…
凶手
killer.
别误会
"Don't take this the wrong way"?
没啦 我有九成九确定你不是 但…
No, no, look. I'm almost 100% certain that you are not,
留在这里比较安全
but the safest option is to be down here.
大家都在…
with all the people…
去死啦
Fuck you.
全都是证人
and the potential witnesses.
你会森七七很正常
That is a completely valid emotional response to have.
- 那也是 - 混蛋
- That too. - Fucking asshole.
干得好
Good job.
去你的 敏蒂
Fuck you, Mindy.
（离开伍兹柏勒）
如果我没写关于你妈的那本书
If I hadn't have written that book about your mother,
- 这一切都不会发生 - 盖儿
- none of this would've happened. - Gale.
- 都是我的错 - 并不是
- I started all of this. - No, you didn't.
是比利鲁米斯的错 我们要做个了结
Billy Loomis started this, and we're gonna end it.
过了今晚不会再有书 电影和鬼脸杀手
After tonight, no more books, no more movies, no more fucking Ghostface.
- 你们不知道法则吗 - 什么法则
- Don't you know the rules? - What rules?
想在恐怖片中活下去
There are specific rules that one.
得有生存法则
must abide by to successfully survive a horror movie.
第一条法则：绝对不能爱爱
For instance, number one…
- 别出去找她 - 她没回我讯息
Don't do it. Don't go outside after her. She's not texting me back.
因为她大概挂了
Because she's probably dead.
天啊 敏蒂 她是我女友 我爱她
Jesus, Mindy. That's my girlfriend, and I love her.
前女友
Was your girlfriend.
你只想看一部我们舅舅被杀的电影
You're just gonna sit and watch a movie about our uncle getting stabbed?
这能让我冷静 好吗我也要哈草
It calms me down, okay? I'm also gonna smoke some weed.
也许跟法兰丝上床
and possibly hook up with Frances.
玩得开心
Have fun.
吼 至少拿个武器吧
Oh, my God, at least take some sort of weapon.
就这个
Here you go.
（找到我再弥补我）
（定位要求）
（丽芙接受定位要求 分享位置）
（愿意与丽芙分享位置吗）
丽芙
Liv?
好吧 不玩了
All right. Okay, yeah, no.
拜托
Please, please, please.
（结束分享位置）
住手 等等
Whoa! Stop! Wait!
太好了 她在开趴
Oh, perfect. She's having a party.
谁会在这时候开趴
Who has a party in the middle of a killing spree?
- 中止计划 - 不 来都来了
- Look, I'm aborting the plan. - No, we're already here.
我会快去快回
I'll go in quickly and get it. I'll be back in five.
我也要去
I'm coming too.
我才不会留在车上等死
If you think I'm waiting out here just to get murdered,
想都别想
you're out of your mind.
塔拉
Tara!
你怎么会出院到处趴趴走好吗
What are you doing out of the hospital? Should you even be up and around?
- 我需要吸入器 - 你要去哪
- I need my spare inhaler. - Why? Where are you going?
没关系 别告诉我 注意安全
It's fine. Don't tell me. I get it. Just be safe, okay?
应该在我房间
I think it's in my room.
大伙儿 多谢光临 但派对结束了
All right, everyone! Thanks for coming, but the party's over!
- 该走人了 - 不要
- Time to go! - Why?
还早啊
But it's so early!
走吧
Let's go.
嘿 拜托 把音乐关掉
Hey, hey, hey! Hello! Can we cut the music, please?
嗨 Z世代 大家好
Uh, hi… Gen Z. How are you? Um…
珊曼和塔拉都被凶手攻击两次
Both Sam and Tara here have been attacked by the killer twice.
她们来了 这地方就是目标 所以…
And now they're here, which makes this place a huge murder target, so…
换作是我就会闪人
if I were you, I would probably leave.
不鸟我是吗快滚
Okay, I tried to be nice. Get the fuck out!
拜托快滚吧
Please get the fuck out.
- 请快滚 - 扫兴鬼
- Sincerely, get the fuck out. - Buzzkill!
谢谢大家 我这是在救你们的小命
Thank you. Thank you all. I'm saving your life. I promise.
谢了 小屁孩
Thanks, teens.
多谢了
Thank you so much.
太好了 乱丢纸杯 多谢了
Thank you for leaving the cup. Thank you.
我是在救你们
Saving your life.
我这是在救你们
I'm saving your life.
救你们的小命 谢谢
Saving your life, thank you.
第三条法则
And number three:
在任何情况下 千万不要说
Never, ever, ever, under any circumstances,
“我马上回来”
say, "I'll be right back."
因为你不会回来
'Cause you won't be back.
有个傻大叔把我们赶出去
Hey, somebody's goofy-ass dad's kicking us out.
可恶
Goddamn it.
谢啦 晚安
Thanks, guys, have a good night.
- 你有我的号码 - 再见
- You have my number. - Bye.
嗨 呃…
Hi. Uh…
还有啤酒吗厨房没有
Is there any beer left? There's none in the kitchen.
有啊 地下室还有
Yes, Richie, there's beer in the basement.
门就在你后面
Right behind you. Basement.
是啊
Yeah.
你想跟我去吗
Do you want to, uh, come with me?
不想 但你是该这么问
No. But you were right to ask.
是啊
Yeah. Um…
好吧 我马上回来
Okay, I'll be right back… Aha!
- 好吧 - 好的
- Yeah. Yeah. - Okay.
他死定了
Well, he's dead.
该死的优步司机给我放鸟
The goddamn fucking Uber canceled on me!
太好了 我不能爱爱也不能回家
Great. Now I can't have sex, and I can't get a ride home.
今晚还会更惨吗
Could this night get any shittier?
丽芙 我哥咧
Liv, where's my brother?
不知道 大概去指控大家是凶手吧
What? I don't know, Mindy. Probably off accusing everyone of being the killer!
他其实是去找你
He actually went looking for you.
我没看到他 好吗
I didn't see him. Okay?
你干嘛那样看我
Why are you looking at me like that?
我在修改嫌犯名单
Just revising my suspect list.
去你的
Fuck this!
你在怕我 敏蒂
Are you afraid of me, Mindy?
你觉得我对你哥做了什么
You think I did something to your brother? Huh?
你觉得我会…杀了你
You think I'm gonna… cut you up?
现在有一点了
A little bit now… yeah.
你明明说我太无趣不会是凶手
I thought you said I was too boring to be the killer.
也许那才是超展开
Maybe that's the twist.
你觉得咧你是专家
What do you think, huh? You're the expert.
你知道专家都有什么下场吗
You know what eventually happens to the expert?
什么
What?
看你的蠢电影吧
Enjoy your stupid movie.
真是个神经病
Fucking psycho.
他们停车了
They stopped.
- 加油站 - 不是
- Gas station? - No. I…
- 惨了 - 怎么了
- Oh, shit. - What?
可恶 还有多远
Oh, shit. How far are we?
太远了
Too far.
该死
Damn it.
塔拉 要走了
Tara, we're leaving!
（席妮皮斯考克来电）
喂
Hello.
你得马上离开那栋房子
You need to get out of that house right now.
你怎么知道我在哪
How do you know where I am?
那是史都马克家 他和你爸杀人的地方
You're in Stu Macher's house, where your dad and Stu killed everyone.
有人把你骗到那里 你得赶快离开
Someone planned to get you there. You need to get the fuck out, Sam!
不 洁美 小心
No, Jamie. Watch out.
小心 洁美
Watch out, Jamie.
你知道他在附近
You know he's around.
- 什么 - 他就在那儿
- What? - There he is.
快啊 转过去 快转过去啊
Come on, man, turn around! Turn around! Dude!
我跟你说了 他就在角落 洁美
I told you. I told you, he's around the corner. Jamie.
- 看看后面 - 不 蓝迪 看看你后面
- Look behind you. - No, Randy, look behind you.
快啊 快转过去
Come on, man, turn around!
猪头 你在干嘛你行的
Dude, what are you doing? You can do it!
那是你的法则 快啊
These are your rules! Own that shit.
在你后面 转过去
Behind you! Turn around.
看看你后面
Look behind…
洁美
Jamie.
噢 惨了
Oh, shit!
我流了很多血
Mindy. That's a lot of blood, Sam.
敏蒂 保持清醒
No, Mindy, stay with me.
你对她做了什么
What did you do to her?
我什么都没做
Nothing. No, I didn't do anything.
- 凶手他… - 她没事吧
- The killer, he… - Mindy!
搞什么鬼
What the fuck?
瑞奇 你去了哪里
Richie, where the fuck were you?
我去地下室拿啤酒
I went into the basement to get beer.
你一个人去地下室
You went to the basement alone?
我叫她跟我去 她不肯
I asked her to come with me! She said no!
给我退后
Fuck! Stay the fuck back.
天啊
Jesus Christ!
我一直陪着塔拉 你们都在趴趴走
I was with Tara, but the rest of you were wandering around.
其中一个是凶手
One of you is the fucking killer!
去你的 安珀
Fuck you, Amber. Fuck you!
- 你的手怎么会有血迹 - 什么
- Why is there blood on your hands? - What?
- 我找到查德 他… - 查德
- I found Chad and he's… - Chad?
- 你在说谎 - 没有
- You're fucking lying. - No.
- 你是凶手 - 我不是
- You're the killer. - No, I'm not.
丽芙 够了
Liv, stop.
- 去你的 - 丽芙 够了
- Fuck you! - Liv, just stop!
去你的 我不是凶手
Fuck you, Amber. I'm not the fucking killer!
我知道
I know.
欢迎来到第三幕
Welcome to act three.
快跑
Run!
我靠
Holy shit!
- 珊曼 快来 - 不
- Sam, come on! - No…
快跑快快快
Run! Go, go, go! Go!
- 天啊 塔拉 - 等等
- Oh, my God… Tara! - Wait, no, Sam.
- 她有枪 - 瑞奇
- She has a gun. - Richie.
而且一定有两个凶手
There are always two killers.
珊曼 把刀放下
Sam, please put the knife down.
我觉得…
Look, I think…
- 另一个凶手可能是塔拉 - 什么
- The other killer might be Tara. - What?
她带我们来这里 你们也很久没见面
She's the one that brought us here, and you two have been estranged for years.
我是说…
I mean,
你对她有多了解
how well do you really know her?
比对你了解的更多
Better than I know you.
等等 珊曼
Sam, wait, whoa. Sam!
肯定出事了
Sounds about right.
准备好了吗
You ready?
准备好当然没有
For this? Never.
上吧
Here we go.
救命啊他刺伤我
Help me, help me! He stabbed me!
- 你觉得呢 - 陷阱
- What do you think? - Trap.
管它的
Fuck it.
盖儿
Gale! Gale!
让我看看
Wait. Let me see. Let me see.
- 你得去医院 - 不
- You got to go to the hospital. - No.
你说要做个了结 去吧 席妮
You said we were gonna finish this. Go finish it, Sidney.
盖儿
Gale.
为了杜威
For Dewey.
躲起来的人 不管是不是凶手 快出来
Anyone hiding, killer or not, you have five seconds to show yourself!
塔拉
Oh, Tara.
天啊
Oh, my God.
珊曼
Sam.
珊曼 拜托
Sam, please.
你好 席妮
Hello, Sidney!
你好 你去了哪儿
Hello there. Where'd you go?
我不是安珀 我是另一个凶手
Oh, this isn't Amber. I'm the other one.
噢 又有两个凶手
Oh. There's two of you. Again.
我看过这部电影
I've seen this movie before.
你没看过这部电影
Not this movie, Sidney.
你真的需要新点子
You really need some new material.
我让你回来了 不是吗
I got you here, didn't I?
你是最没有创意的一个
You might actually be the most derivative one of all.
拜托 同一栋房子
I mean, Christ, the same house?
也许吧 但你忘了第一条生存法则
Maybe so. But you forgot the first rule of surviving a Stab movie.
- 绝对不能接… - 太无聊了 等等
Never answer the… - I'm bored. - Wait!
把手举起来你在这里干嘛
Put your hands up! Show me your hands! What are you doing in there?
躲避凶手啊 我叫你出来
Hiding from murderers. I told you to come out!
才不要你会向我开枪
I'm not gonna come out! You're shooting everything!
靠北 是鬼脸杀手
Holy shit, it's Ghostface!
瑞奇 快去拿枪
Richie! Gun. Get the gun.
你射伤我的腿很难耶
Yeah, kind of hard since you shot me in the leg.
- 好耶 - 向他开枪
- Yes! Yes! - Shoot him!
幸好你没事
Thank God you're okay.
因为我真的
'Cause I really,
很想亲手杀了你
really wanted to be the one to kill you.
坐下来 皮斯考克
Sit the fuck down, Prescott!
这一招真的奏效了
I can't believe this worked.
我知道 凶手就是我
I know. It's a bummer it's me.
但我是这部电影最好的人选
But it really was the best choice for the movie.
这不是电影
This isn't a fucking movie!
以后会改编成电影
No. But it will be.
- 这才是重点 对吧安珀 - 对啊
- That's the point, right, Amber? - Right, hon!
第三幕大屠杀 有 凶手揭晓 有
Third act bloodbath, check. Killers revealed, check.
该上演大结局了
Time for the big finale!
- 瑞奇… - 嘘嘘
- Richie… - Shh, shh…
好了 好了
Okay. Okay.
把他们带到厨房
Let's get 'em into the kitchen.
走吧 贱货
Let's go, bitch!
总得有人拯救这个电影系列
Someone has to save the franchise.
第一集《惊声尖叫》后就没有好的续集
You see, no one has made a great Stab movie since the first one.
真的没有
Not really.
宝贝 去把前任莱利太太拖进来
Hey, baby, you want to go get the very ex-Mrs. Riley?
没问题
Yeah, I do.
嘿
Hey, hey!
别乱来
Whoa… whoa.
席妮皮斯考克
Sidney Prescott.
你要知道…
You know…
我是你真正的铁粉
I'm a really big fan.
去你的
Go fuck yourself.
看过上一集吗 我不爱看恐怖片
You see the last Stab movie? Not really a fan of scary movies.
算你聪明 那部电影烂透了
That checks out. Anyway, it sucked balls.
因为没人在乎真正的粉丝
Because nobody takes the true fans seriously.
大家只会笑我们 为什么
They just laugh at us, and why?
因为我们热爱恐怖片
Because we love something?
我们只是个笑话
We're just a fucking joke to them?
迷文化怎么会有毒
How can fandom be toxic?
我们只是爱看电影
It's about love!
他们不知道这些电影对粉丝有多重要
They don't fucking understand that these movies are important to people.
- 瑞奇… - 但我们会帮他们
- Richie… - We're gonna help them!
好莱坞早就没有新点子
Hollywood's totally fucking out of ideas,
我们就决定给他们全新的题材
so we decided we'd give them some new source material to follow.
回归基本故事概念
You know, bring it back to basics.
才能拍出伟大的《惊声尖叫》电影
Because that's how you make a great Stab movie, Sam.
改编自真实事件
"Based on actual events."
- 盖儿 - 给我坐好
- Gale. - Shh, shh.
退后
Back up. Back up.
你们这么做只是让我当电影的英雄
You did all this just to make me the hero of your fucked-up movie?
亲爱的 你不是英雄
Sweetie, you're not the hero.
你是大反派
You're the villain.
会看到她老爸比利鲁米斯幻影的女儿
The daughter of Billy Loomis who sees fucked-up visions of her dead dad?
席妮皮斯考克杀死你爸
Sidney Prescott killed your father.
你…
You…
做的一切都是为了把她带回伍兹柏勒
did all this just to get her back to Woodsboro.
知道这些电影最大的问题是什么
You know what the biggest problem with the Stab movies is?
没有麦克迈尔斯或杰森沃尔希斯
There's no Michael Myers or Jason Voorhees.
没有一直回来的大坏蛋
No bad guy to keep coming back.
但是第一集凶手的私生女
But the illegitimate daughter of the original mastermind?
那才是超屌的大反派
Now that's a fucking villain.
- 你怎么知道 - 你爸的事
- How did you know? - About your father?
这是个小镇 你妈又是酒鬼
It's a small town, and your mom's a drunk!
我在电影版认识瑞奇
I met Richie on the Stab subreddit.
我爸妈买下这房子后我就着迷了
I've been obsessed ever since my parents bought this house.
我们很快发现彼此有一样的点子
We realized pretty quickly we had similar ideas.
要在莫德斯托找到你并不难
Wasn't that hard for me to find you in Modesto.
要上你也不难
It wasn't that hard for me to fuck you, either.
但我猜性活跃的女人
But I guess being a sexually available woman.
现在算是女权人士
is supposed to be empowering these days.
去你的
Fuck you!
你只是在引用原版电影
Well, now you're just quoting the original.
但光是有你还不够
But it wouldn't work with just you, Sam.
我们还得把经典角色找回来
See, we had to bring the legacy characters back to make it matter.
没有洁美李就不算 正宗的《月光光心慌慌》
Can't have a bona fide Halloween without Jamie Lee!
没错
Nope!
杜威得死才够真实
Dewey had to die to make it real.
证明这不只是乱掰一通
To show that this wasn't just some bullshit,
只为了赚钱的劣级续集电影
cash-in, run-of-the-mill sequel.
因为我们的电影真的会死人
Because our movie has fucking stakes!
谁都会在重启续集领便当
'Cause anyone can die in a requel.
不
No!
靠北 喂
Goddamn it. Whoa, whoa!
喂 给我乖乖坐好
No, hey! Sit the fuck down.
真的很抱歉 席妮
I'm so sorry, Sid.
我们也不能饶过你 你老是死不了…
We can't let you live either. I mean, surviving this many times…
未免也太扯了吧
that would just be ridiculous.
这次粉丝才会是赢家
This time the fans are gonna be the ones who win.
- 都说完了吧 - 说得真好
- That about cover it? - Nailed it, baby.
把塔拉拖出来 开始布置尸体
Get Tara out of the closet. We got to start staging the bodies!
别死 席妮 别死
Stay with me, Sid. Stay with me.
你真的应该听杜威的话
You really should've listened to Dewey.
被他说中了 凶手是恋爱对象
He nailed it in one! Dude, look at the love interest!
你是脑残吗
Are you fucking stupid?
我甚至让你怀疑你老妹
I even had you convinced it could be your sister.
她不在耶
Um, she's not here.
她不在是什么意思
What the fuck do you mean, "She's not here"?
她不在这里
She's not here!
我替她松绑了
I untied her.
你也没那么有说服力嘛
Guess you're not as persuasive as you thought.
（未知来电）
打给你的
That's for you.
你的跛脚老妹改变不了什么
Yeah. Like your gimpy little sister's gonna make a difference.
她已经被捅了N刀了
She's our fucking pincushion at this point.
安珀 到处找 她不可能跑太远
Amber! Fan out. She couldn't have gotten far.
找不到她
I can't find her!
安珀
Amber?
珊曼 你去哪就快上演大结局了
Sam! Where you going? Your big scene's coming up!
我要杀了你
Fucking kill you!
干洗手凝露
The fucking hand sanitizer?
不不不 不是我的错
No, no, no, it's not my fault! It's not my fault!
让我猜 你是被电影逼的
Let me guess, the movies made you do it?
都是留言区的酸民逼的啦
No, it was the message boards! I was radicalized.
- 电影粉丝 - 对 他们超极端
- By movie fans? - Yes, they're so mad!
不是我的错 我是个傻妞
Please, it's not my fault. I'm just a dumb kid.
只想有参与感
I wanted to be a part of something.
参与感你杀死我最好的朋友
"A part of something"? You killed my best friend!
是啊 他死得很窝囊
Yeah, and he died like a pussy.
砍杀恐怖片就是这样
That's the thing about slashers, Sam.
总是留下一堆血迹
So many blood trails.
这是你的血迹吗
This one yours?
我来解谜啰
Only one way to find out!
杜威死前也是看到我
I was the last thing Dewey saw before he died too.
我不敢相信能亲手杀了你们
I can't believe I get to do you both.
这次没有救兵 你的故事结束了
No last-minute saves this time. Your story's over!
该让别人接棒了
Time to pass the torch.
你来接棒吧 贱货
It's all yours, bitch!
- 你要动手吗 - 这个是你的
- You want to do the honors? - This one's yours.
不要很抱歉杀了杜威
No, stop, stop, stop! I'm sorry about Dewey.
去死吧
Fuck you.
这下你真的火了
Enjoy that torch.
不要…
Stop…
搞砸…
fucking up…
我的大结局
my ending!
珊曼
Sam?
Sam!
好吧
Okay.
你现在要怎样
What are you gonna do now, huh?
打恐怖电话给我
Make a scary phone call to me?
戴着鬼脸面具从衣橱跳出来
Pop out of that closet in a Ghostface mask?
不行
No.
因为你是大反派
Because you're the villain!
大反派最后都会死
And the villain dies at the end.
这就是规则
Those are the rules.
我有一条新规则
I'm introducing a new rule.
什么规则
And what would that be? Huh?
说啊
Well?
别惹毛连环杀手的女儿
Never fuck with the daughter of a serial killer.
那…我的结局呢
What about… my ending?
这就来了
Here it comes.
小心 他们会再回来
Careful, they always come back.
搞定了
Okay, then.
我还是比较喜欢《鬼敲门》
I still prefer The Babadook.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
- 你呢 - 嗯
- Are you good? - Mm-hmm.
抱歉 我先失陪了
I'm so sorry. Excuse me.
抱歉 先生
Excuse me, sir.
她不会有事
She's gonna be okay.
能不能带我们到别家医院
Can you take us to a different hospital this time?
准备好了吗
You ready to go?
我马上回来
I'll be right back, yeah?
席妮 盖儿
Sidney. Gale.
谢谢你们
Thank you both.
为我做的一切
For everything.
你们不会有事吧
Are you gonna be all right?
我死不了 每次都这样
I'll survive. I always do.
你说的对
You were right…
我不该逃跑
about not running.
很抱歉
Sorry about that.
你还好吧
How are you doing?
过几天再问我
Ask me in a few days.
但至少我知道要写什么
But at least I know what I'm gonna write about.
你要写什么
What's that?
不是这一切
Not this.
不能让那两个混蛋出名
Those fuckers can die in anonymity.
我要写一个在这里当过警长的好男人
But maybe something about a good man who used to be the sheriff here once.
我很想看这故事
I'd like to read that story.
我能问个怪问题吗
Can I ask you a weird question?
可以啊
Yeah.
我会没事吗
Am I gonna be okay?
最后一定会
Eventually.
- 嘿 - 等等 珊曼
- Hey. - Wait. Sam, Sam, Sam!
谢谢
Thank you.
我不会再丢下你
Well, you're not going anywhere without me.
放心
Don't worry.
我会一直握着你的手
I'm gonna hold your hand all the way there.
25年前的这时候 就在这栋房子
Twenty-five years ago, almost to the day, in this very house.
一场悲剧结束
a tragic story ended.
今晚 全新的篇章也将结束
Tonight, a new chapter came to a close.
警方目前仍在搜证
Police do not have a lot of information right now,
掌握的线索不多
as they are still collecting evidence.
但这是一个死伤惨重的犯罪现场
As you can see, this is a very active crime scene here.
没有实际的伤亡人数
An unknown number of fatalities, several injuries,
有些伤患正被救护车送去医院
some people being taken off by ambulance right now as we speak.
这是持续发展的新闻…
This is a developing story…
献给卫斯
For Wes.